PRINCIPAL SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Summary

Over 15 years of experience in various domains that includes Service management, Enterprise Change Management, build and deployment solutions. Have worked towards creating highly quality products in the capacities of Principal Engineer and Development Manager. Specialized in creating and maintaining products that spans multiple technologies Agile practitioner, certified Scrum Master Specialties: Domain: Service Management, ITIL, Enterprise change management Cloud Computing & SaaS, Service Oriented Architecture (SOA) Java, JavaScript related technologies Agile methodology

Highlights

Visual C++ 6.0 Database: MS-Access, MS-SQL Server 7.0. Platform: Windows 98 / NT 4.0

Experience

Bickford Senior Living

- Development Environment: UNIX, ANSI C, C++, VB, X Windows Systems, OSF/MOTIF, ORACLE SM relational database, TCP/IP-based networking ENMAC stands for Electricity Network Management and Control, which is a product of GE Harris Energy Control Systems for electricity network management.
- Roles & responsibilities: My task was to Design and Implement Enhancement Features for ENMAC.
- I have designed and developed Prototype implementation for 'Alarm management' functionality in ENMAC.
- The Development for the prototype was done using X/Motif.
- I have used COM with win32 API for handling messages from the User Interface.
- The Implementation was done using C & C++.
- At Mahindra British Telecom: Client: Willet Language: C & C+++ Platform: SCO Unix 5.0.
- Willett is a leading international manufacturer and single source supplier of industrial coding, labeling and bar code printing products.
- The embedded environment comprises of an 80186 processor with associated memory modules, flash monitor, Serial Input Outputs, DMA, RTC and a LCD Monitor and keyboard.
- The software is developed and maintained in the UNIX/C environment.
- The development was done in C/C++ on Unix.
- Responsibilities: Was involved in design, development, and testing of Software for printers.
- Writing C functions to create and edit the print messages.
- Development of new menus for hardware control.
- C and C++ Functions and classes respectively for remote PC control Handling of interrupt from various hardware sources, DMA handling etc.
- User Interface development in Hindi and Thai languages Editor support to allow the user to enter language specific characters Appropriate keyboard mapping for each language Processing of language specific rules Font development (bitmaps) for the various font sizes System testing.
- Dry Rig testing.
- Implementation in C /C++ on Unix.

Principal software Engineer 01/2008 to 01/2013

- Expert in C++, Distributed Systems Have been working on CA SCM (CA Cloud Service Management) Bamboo release. Finished the
 design and development for Custom connector feature and process designer service e operations delete and copy functionality Was part of
 CA Cloud Service Management release 1.0 which is called lotus Designed and developed the credential vault feature Designed the Key
 store feature for the CA CSM solution Implemented Metering feature for hours saved for the work flow executions Skills: Java, J2EE Web
 services, ODATA,REST API Database SQL Server Unit testing: JUnit, Mockito, Jmockit Eclipse Link, hibernate Previous work
 experience at CA Joined CA on 1st March 2004 as a Senior Software Engineer for the Software Change Manager Team.
- Was the first Developer on SCM at ITC and have been continuing with the same team till date.
- Currently working as a Principal Software engineer Initially I have taken the responsibility of building the team technically.
- Have provided SCM training and knowledge transfer to the team which grew to around 10 in 1 year.
- I was responsible for resolving the L2 issues and delivering the new features for r7.0 Key Achievements as team lead and Manger role in SCM from (2005-2008) Ensuring the Issues resolved by the team in timely manner.
- Deliver the features for r7.1 and r12 releases on time.
- Provide technical leadership to the team during the release.
- Designing the new features.
- Developed a quick SCM integration with Quality center for a POC for GWL customer which later became the SOIAB product.
- Developed a POC for integration with Clarity.
- Contributed to ideas around change and release management integration with SCM Designed and developed Java based Build Automation Framework for automating the build process for projects in SCM Have been a good technical mentor for the team.

Design Engineer 04/2001 to 02/2004 Raytheon Technologies Corp Omaha

- The John F.
- Welch Technology Centre (JFWTC), Bangalore, is General Electric's first and largest Research and Development Centre outside the US.
- I Have worked for GE Power systems and GE Medical systems .For more details about the company visit http://gejfwtc.com/ & /www.gehealthcare.com/Mahindra British Telecom, Mumbai is a leading India-based global IT solutions provider.
- MBT is focused on creating sustainable value growth through innovative solutions and unique partnerships.
- For more details about the company visit http://www.mahindrabt.com.

- Projects at Previous Organisations At GE Wipro GE Medical Systems DLS CT-PET Language: C++ on Solaris, Linux Tools: Rational
 ClearCase, Middleware: ECOMM The DLS CT-PET Program involves development and maintenance of the Host Subsystem of the DLS
 PET scanner.
- The development environment is on C,C++ on UNIX.
- The source code is managed with Rational Clearcase having multisite configuration to synchronize the parallel developments done across the Globe.
- Knowledge in clearcase is indispensable here.
- Responsibilities: As a Design Engineer my set of responsibilities comprises of the following: Worked mainly on Bug Fixes and Enhancements
 to the software.
- Coded mostly on C & C++ on Unix.
- Developed UI's using X/Motif & TCL/TK.
- Used shell scripting forbuilding, packaging the software and maintaining the applications that run on the host GE Oil and Gas Language: C++/VC++6.0 Database: Oracle 8.0/9.0 Platform: Windows NT 4.0, Windows XP GE Oil and Gas' Stutensee team uses four methods to estimate depth of cracks from B and C scans Mean maximum amplitude, acoustic shadows, crack tip indicators and overlap values.
- The ray-tracing algorithm uses tips of cracks to estimate their depths.
- This project seeks develop the algorithm and to encapsulate it into a dll so that it can be plugged into PRIMUS Responsibilities: As a Design Engineer my set of responsibilities comprises of the following: Responsible for Design and development of two Modules MTAParser' and 'RTA'.
- EPS Client: GE Power Systems Language: VB, ASP, JavaScript, XML, XSL Database: Oracle 8.0 EPS (e-Product Service) is GEPS
 Service Portal, online web based system providing Product Services information for field/service engineers to reduce cycle time in service
 calls.
- Key features are data integration, single point access and simplified workflow The Portal is developed using XPS server Roles & responsibilities: Developed and delivered two CDA's (Content Delivery Agents) 'As Built Drawings' and 'Document Management'.
- Developed and delivered two CDA's (Content Delivery Agents) 'As Built Drawings' and 'Document Management'.
- As Built Drawings' CDA Digitizes the manual process involved when the Field Engineer makes changes to the 'As Is' Drawings when the Turbine is Installed.
- The CDA provides User Interface for filling out the necessary Information about the changes to the Drawings.
- I have implemented functionalities for storing the information in the database, Sending automatic mails to the Concerned Coe's, and Creating clarify cases.
- I have done my Green belt Project on this CDA.
- I have developed the Upload feature by implementing an Activex Component, which will send email from the client machine with attachments.
- The Attachments are then parsed on the server by an application and stores them on the Document Server.
- I have implemented the user interface for the CDA's using XML and XSLT.
- The functionalities for the CDA's were implemented using VB.

Education

Bachelor of Technology: Electronics and Communication Engineering Warangal 1999 National Institute of Technology Unix shell, Perl Tools: Installshield, Install Anywhere Database: Oracle, SQL Server Communication Infrastructure: PEC Qualification Electronics and Communication Engineering Warangal

Skills

Activex, AIX, API, ASP, Automation, C, ANSI C, C++, clarify, ClearCase, COM, CA, hardware, Content, Client, Database, Delivery, LCD, Designing, Document Management, Eclipse, edit, Editor, email, Engineer, Features, filling, flash, Hindi, HPUX, http, MVS, Installshield, J2EE, Java, JavaScript, keyboard, languages, leadership, team lead, Linux, lotus, MacOS, memory, mentor, access, MS-Access, MS-SQL Server 7.0, win, Windows, Windows 98, Windows NT 4.0, NT 4.0, Windows XP, Middleware, Motif, OSF/MOTIF, Network Management, networking, Oil, os, Operating System, ORACLE, Oracle 8.0, Developer, packaging, Perl, printers, coding, Programming, Quality, quick, RedHat, relational database, Research, scanner, SCO Unix 5.0, shell scripting, Solaris, SQL Server, TCL/TK, TCP/IP, Telecom, Thai, unique, UNIX, UNIX / C, Unix shell, User Interface, VB, VC++6.0, Visual C++ 6.0, workflow, X Windows, XML, XSL, XSLT